How many of them were AI experts
before they started?
None of them
You are not behind.
You do not need to know everything
about AI. Start with one small
task. Ask clearly. Inspect what AI
gives you, and only after checking
it, use it.
Pooja is training as an electrician
and needs to prepare materials for
tomorrow's practical.
Pooja asked the AI for a visual, step by
step guide to installing and testing
earthing plate.
As the instructions and images rendered
on screen, she cross-references them with
her practical notebook.
Satisfied with the line details, she put
them to use.
Sameer is a commerce student,
working on a cash flow and ratio
analysis assignment.
He gives a company's report to AI
to generate the analysis.
The AI generated the entire
assignment in seconds but as soon
as Sameer read the initial lines
of the output he realized
something was off.
The AI claimed that the company
launched an EV charging stations
with direct government subsidy of
15,000 crores.
Sameer checked the report and found the
correct details.
The investment was for the Jamnagar Giga
project.
Sameer pointed out the incorrect
details to the AI and requested
it to fix the data.
After Sameer highlighted the error,
AI corrected the output.
AI can help us work faster,
but its answers should always be
verified.
Meet Neha, a store manager who
needs to identify top selling,
trending, and under performing
products.
To save time, she uploads her
sales report to AI for analysis.
The AI generated a quick dashboard
summary. Neha now side by side
cross checks the AI's high
selling, trending and low selling
categories with the actual store
report.
After comparing every figure, Neha
looks completely satisfied. The AI
output matches her actual sales
data perfectly.
This is Arjun. He works at Meadow
View college and needs to inform
students about a college
orientation. He asks AI to shorten
the notice while keeping all
important details.
AI gives him a shorter version and
he checks the important details.
The facts match, now he can use it.
They used AI for different
everyday tasks, but one common
rule.
Ask, inspect, and use.